As you may have noticed,
你可能已经注意到了
stochastic policy search may or may not always work as expected.
随机性策略搜索并非始终能达到预期效果
It is sensitive to the choice of individual samples and may
它容易受到所选单个样本的影响
get stuck in local optima or take a long time to converge.
可能会陷入局部最佳状态或需要很长的时间才能收敛
One of the main reasons to use such a randomized approach
使用此类随机化方法的主要原因之一是
is that you don't need to know anything about the objective function,
你不需要了解关于目标函数
the underlying policy or it's gradient.
底层策略或梯度的任何信息
You can treat it like a black box.
可以当做一个黑匣子
Send in a set of parameters,
输入一组参数
run the policy in the environment,
在环境中运行策略
and get an objective value.
并获得目标值
But if you knew more about the policy,
但是如果你对策略
and the objective function,
和目标函数更了解
and if you could compute the gradient of
并且如果能计算目标函数
the objective function with respect to policy parameters,
相对于策略参数的梯度
that would allow you to take more efficient steps, right?
这样可以采取更有效的步骤 对吧
The gradient always points towards the direction of maximum change.
梯度始终指向最大变化的方向
So, instead of having to evaluate a bunch of
因此 不用评估当前策略临近区域的
random candidates in the current policies neighborhood,
一堆随机候选策略
you can directly compute the next set of policy parameters that seem most promising.
你可以直接计算下一组看起来最有希望最佳的策略参数
This is the basis of policy gradients.
这就是策略梯度的基础
The general layout of such an approach would be to
此类方法的一般流程是
find the gradient for the current policy parameters,
找到当前策略参数的梯度
update them in the direction of increasing gradient, and iterate.
并以增加梯度的形式更新它们 然后迭代
Know that we still want to be cautious and take
注意 我们依然需要保持谨慎
small steps defined by our step size alpha.
并采取由步长 α 定义的小步
This is because both our policy and the environment are most likely stochastic.
因为策略和环境最有可能是随机性
Each policy evaluation may not produce consistent results.
每个策略评估可能无法生成一致的结果
This is one reason to evaluate a policy over multiple episodes.
这是通过多个阶段评估策略的原因之一
Now, if your objective function is not differentiable,
如果目标函数不可微
which is possible if the underlying policy is complicated,
底层策略很复杂时会发生这种情况
you will not be able to find the gradient directly.
你将无法直接找到梯度
In that case, you can estimate the gradient using finite differences.
在这种情况下 你可以使用有限差估算梯度
Given any policy pi that is defined by an n dimensional parameter vector theta,
对于任何一个策略 π 它由 n 维参数向量 θ 定义
find the partial derivative of the objective function
找到目标函数相对于
with respect to each dimension k. By adding
每个维度 k 的偏导数
a tiny value to that particular dimension and computing
使该维度与一个很小的值相加
the difference between the resulting policy value and the current one,
计算形成的策略与当前策略之间的差异
collect all the partial derivatives into a single vector to get the combined derivative.
将所有偏导数添加到一个向量中 获得组合导数
Note that each of these policy evaluations may require
注意 每个策略评估都需要
at least to one full episode of interaction in the environment,
至少与环境完成一次完整的互动阶段
and we are doing one evaluation for every parameter dimension at every iteration.
并且在每次迭代时对每个参数维度进行一次评估
So, this procedure can take a long time.
因此 这一流程可能会花费很长的时间
If you do have access to the underlying policy function,
如果你可以访问底层策略函数
presumably because you designed it,
假设因为你设计了该函数
then it is more efficient to try and compute the gradient analytically.
那么可以更高效地以分析方式尝试和计算梯度
But this means we need to compute the gradient of
但是这就意味着我们需要计算某个函数的
the expected value of some function. That sounds hard.
预期值的梯度 听起来有点难
Well, it turns out this is a fairly well studied problem.
实际上这是一个得到广泛研究的问题
The reward function we have here is generally referred to as a "score function",
这里的奖励函数通常称之为得分函数
and we can manipulate this expression to
我们可以操纵该表达式
estimate the gradient of the score function more easily.
以便更轻松地估算得分函数的梯度
Let's see how. To simplify things,
我们来看看如何计算 为了进行简化
we'll consider some arbitrary score function f that is dependent on x.
我们将考虑某个依赖于 x 的随机得分函数 f
The values of x are drawn from a probability distribution defined by parameters theta.
值 x 来自由参数 θ 定义的概率分布
This means we can expand the expectation into
这意味着我们可以将预期函数展开为
an integral or summation of the probability of x given theta times the score function.
一个积分或 x|θ 的概率乘以得分函数的和
Note that here the gradient can be moved into the summation.
注意 这里的梯度可以移到求和运算中
This will help us simplify things a bit further.
这样可以进一步简化公式
Now, we can use something called the Likelihood Ratio Trick.
现在我们可以使用似然比技巧
First, we multiply the numerator and denominator by P of X given theta,
首先 我们将分子和分母乘以 P[X|θ}
and then replace the resulting fraction by the derivative of the log probability.
然后将生成的分数替换为对数概率的导数
Trust me, this is a well-known identity.
相信我 这是一个很有名的技巧
Finally, we can convert the summation back to an expectation.
最后 我们将求和变回预期函数
Now, know that we only need to compute the derivative of the log probabilities,
注意 我们只需计算对数概率的导数
not the score function since it does not directly depend on theta.
而不是得分函数 因为它并不直接依赖于 θ
Back in reinforcement land,
回到强化部分
here's what the gradient expression looks like.
这是梯度表达式
With the policy function pi in place of the probability distribution,
用策略函数 π 替换概率分布
and our own score function R,
以及我们自己的得分函数 R
which can be the sum of all rewards,
它可以是所有奖励或折扣奖励的和
discounted rewards or some other value-based function.
或者其他基于值的函数
You must be wondering like I did when I first saw this,
你可能会疑问 就像我第一次见到该表达式一样
did we actually gain anything from this whole exercise?
我们从这整个练习中获得了任何结果吗？
It looks just about as ugly as before.
看起来和之前的一样糟糕
Let's look at it carefully.
我们来仔细看看它
We can compute the score function by interacting
我们可以通过与环境互动并对获得的奖励求和
with the environment and summing up the rewards we get.
计算得分函数
If we had a policy function implemented using some approximator like a neural net,
如果我们有一个使用神经网络等估算器实现的策略函数
then we can compute the log of the output probabilities and the derivative.
那么我们可以计算输出概率的对数以及导数
Libraries like TensorFlow or PyTorch will happily do this for us.
TensorFlow 或 PyTorch 等库可以帮助我们完成这一步
And finally, we can compute this expectation
最后 我们可以通过抽取一批不同的样本
stochastically by taking a bunch of different samples.
以随机方式计算这个预期函数
Using this gradient, we can update
我们可以使用这个梯度更新策略参数
policy parameters to improve the objective function iteratively.
从而以迭代方式改善目标函数
So, we can actually build a concrete algorithm around this.
因此我们可以根据它构建一个具体的算法